wisd.us 2013-05-20

# Weslaco ISD ::

WISD Privacy Statement

**Weslaco Independent School District Website Privacy Statement**

Weslaco Independent School District (hereinafter referred to as Weslaco ISD) is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Privacy Statement applies to data collection and usage on Weslaco ISD sites and services and governs data collection and usage. It does not apply to any third party websites linked to this website. The Weslaco ISD website is a general audience web site, intended for users of all ages. Personal information of all users is collected, used and disclosed as described in this Privacy Statement. By using the Weslaco ISD Website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

  * Accessibility Standards Compliance 508
  * Collection of Your Personal Information
  * Use of Your Personal Information
  * Security of Your Personal Information
  * Use of Cookies
  * Enforcement of Privacy Statement
  * Contact Information
  * Student Information: Family Rights and Privacy Act - (pertaining to student records and information) 
  * Custodian of Records
  * Parent Access
  * Student Access
  * Directory Information
  * Types of Student Records
  * Access Log
  * Release of Student Records Without Prior Consent
  * Parents Rights to Review and Challenge Educational Records ****

**508 Accessibility**

Section 508 aims to provide Federal employees with disabilities access to office systems and information equal to their non-disabled colleagues. It also ensures that people in the general public who have disabilities, have equal access to Government information.

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

On some sections of this website, Weslaco ISD collects personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Weslaco ISD also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your zip code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and favorites.

Weslaco ISD may collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken within the Weslaco ISD website. We may also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring Web site addresses.

Return to top

**Use of Your Personal Information**

Weslaco ISD collects and uses your personal information to operate the Weslaco ISD website and deliver the services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content and promotional materials about District events or programs. Weslaco ISD may also send you surveys regarding current services or potential new services that may be offered.

Weslaco ISD does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Weslaco ISD may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Weslaco ISD may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Weslaco ISD, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Weslaco ISD does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Weslaco ISD may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the Weslaco ISD or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of the Weslaco ISD; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Weslaco ISD website or members of the public.

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United States.

Return to top

**Security of Your Personal Information**

Weslaco ISD is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. A variety of security technologies and procedures are used to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, the personal information you provide on computer systems are stored on systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When highly confidential information is transmitted over the Internet, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Return to top

**Use of Cookies**

Weslaco ISD uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize Weslaco ISD web pages, or register with our website, a cookie helps to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, preferred email address, and so on. When you return to the Weslaco ISD website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Weslaco ISD website features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the our website.

Return to top

**Enforcement of Privacy Statement**

Changes to Privacy Statement Weslaco ISD will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect district and customer feedback. Weslaco ISD encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how your information is being protected.

Return to top

**Contact Information**

Weslaco ISD welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you believe that Weslaco ISD has not adhered to this Statement, please contact:

Jeffrey W. Harris, M.Ed, RTSBA

Technology Director

Weslaco Independent School District

319 W. Fourth Street

Weslaco , TX 78596

Return to top

**Student Information: Family Rights and Privacy Act**

**Custodian of Records**

The Family Rights and Privacy Act of 1974, and Senate Bill 1493, establish notification procedures concerning student records. Selected code sections and District procedures are included in this pamphlet in an effort to inform parents whose children are enrolled in the Weslaco ISD of their rights related to educational records.

Return to top

**Parent Access**

Student cummulative records may be reviewed and inspected by the adoptive parent or legal guardian of a student or either natural parent in the presence of a certificated employee (even if there is a restraining order against the parent) unless a specific restriction to student records is ordered. However, only the parent who has legal custody of the student may challenge the contents of the records or authorize the release of records.

Return to top

**Student Access**

Students who have attained the age of eighteen years or who are attending an institution of post secondary education have the right to review and have access to records accorded to the parents. Students may contact their high school counselor concerning review and access to their records.

Students who are 16 years of age or older or have completed the 10th grade have the right to review their records. Such a review shall be for a specific educational purpose and shall be conducted in the presence of a certificated staff member.

Return to top

**Directory Information**

Directory information means one or more of the following items: Student's name, address, date and place of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, picture, weight and height of members of athletic teams, grade average, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, and the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student. Using discretion based upon the best interest of the student, directory information may be released by the educational staff to local, state, county and federal agencies such as law enforcement, probation, protective, adoption, and health agencies, employers, scholarship award committees, private business or professional schools, military services recruitment representatives, or any public agency working on the behalf of minors. Parents are advised that, should they not want directory information to be released, they must notify the principal of the school in writing on an annual basis within thirty days after the first day of school enrollment.

Return to top

**Types of Student Records**

Release of pupil information other than directory information to a person or agency requires the prior written consent of parents. The district will respond to subpoenas by sending the appropriate records to the court or the attorney representing the student. Types of student records, location, and person to contact are identified in this brochure for the convenience of parents and/or students 18 years or older who wish to give consent for the release of student records.

**Types of Student Records**

| 

**Location**

| 

**Contact**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Registration Forms (family)

| 

School

| 

Principal  
  
Test Record Card (test scores)

| 

School/Research Annex

| 

Principal: Counselor  
  
Health Record

| 

School and/or Health Department

| 

Principal: District Health Office  
  
Student Progress Reports (subject achievement)

| 

School

| 

Principal: Counselor  
  
Attendance Record/SARB

| 

School

| 

Principal: Youth Services  
  
Discipline/Expulsion Records

| 

School

| 

Principal: Hearing Panel  
  
Special Records - Speech and/or Special Education Programs (special program needs)

| 

School and/or Educational Services

| 

Principal: Program Coordinator  
  
Enrollment History (schools attended)

| 

School/Student Records

| 

Student Records  
  
Work Experience Records

| 

Educational Services

| 

Work Experience Specialist  
  
Guidance Studies

| 

Psychological Services

| 

Coordinator, Psychological Services  
  
Sociological Records

| 

Sociological Services

| 

Sociological Specialist  
  
Family Data

| 

School

| 

Principal: Coordinator  
  
A charge of $0.10 per page will be made to parents or guardians requesting more than two copies of student records. Pupil anecdotal records which are not accessible to others and solely used by educational personnel are not considered educational pupil records.  
  
Return to top

**Access Log**

A log which lists those persons, agencies, or organizations requesting or receiving information from a student's record is maintained in the student's pupil record. Those who do not need to complete the access log include parents, parties to whom written consent has been given, and school officials or employees who have an educational interest in the student.

Return to top

**Release of Student Records Without Prior Consent**

Student records may be released to the following without prior consent:

  * School officials; educational staff of a school.
  * Officials of another school district in which the student is enrolled.
  * Comptroller General of United States.
  * The Secretary of Health, Education & Welfare (HEW), or an administrative head of an educational agency.
  * Local, State and Federal educational and protective agencies.
  * Personnel related to financial aid applications.
  * State and local law enforcement officials to whom information is specifically required to be reported or disclosed.
  * Organizations conducting special studies which will not permit the personal identification of students.
  * Accrediting agencies.
  * Parents of dependent student as defined in Section 152 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954.
  * Judicial order or subpoena, provided a reasonable effort is made to notify the parent in advance of compliance.
  * Health or safety emergency agencies.

Return to top

**Parents Rights to Review and Challenge Educational Records**

  * Parents or legal guardians have the right to inspect and review their child(ren)'s records within five days of their request. School records are to be reviewed in the presence of a certificated school employee.
  * Students who have attained eighteen years of age or are attending a post secondary school have the right to review their records. Students may contact their school counselor to review and inspect their records.
  * A parent with physical custody may request a hearing challenge any educational record which he/she believes to be inaccurate, misleading or inappropriate, and request removal of such record. Parents should request a hearing with the school principal.
  * A written statement regarding a challenged educational record may be made and included in the educational record if so desired by the custodial parent.
  * Parents may request in writing a hearing with the Custodian of Records regarding the unresolved challenge of educational records.
  * When disputes cannot be resolved by the Custodian, parents may submit a written request for a hearing to the Superintendent of Schools.
  * If a request is unresolved by the Superintendent's Hearing Panel, the parent may submit in writing within thirty days a request for review by the Board of Education. If the Board of Education sustains the allegations, the information must be destroyed. If the Board of Education denies the allegations, the parent may submit a written statement to be included in the student's educational record.
  * Parents may file a complaint with the United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare regarding a failure on the part of the District to grant appropriate rights.

Return to top
